<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[dougsko]]></title>
  <link href="http://dougsko.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dougsko.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-19T12:13:53-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://dougsko.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Doug Prostko]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grow Log - 8/18/13]]></title>
    <link href="http://dougsko.github.io/blog/2013/08/18/grow-log-8-slash-18-slash-13/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-18T10:12:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://dougsko.github.io/blog/2013/08/18/grow-log-8-slash-18-slash-13</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Everything is growing pretty well.  I planted two more cubes with pepper
seeds from Hawaii today.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/JvWMSlw.jpg" title="'plants'" >
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/ymAtPg8.jpg" title="'plants2'" ></p>

<p>Most of the plants are starting to grow their secondary set of leaves so
hopefully I can start identifying some of them soon.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/MUE5JYq.jpg" title="'closeup'" >
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/Xo49WHN.jpg" title="'closeup 1'" >
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/FfPGJDD.jpg" title="'closeup 2" >
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/i4LnSuF.jpg" title="'closeup 3" >
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/ADefNh7.jpg" title="'table'" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding a support bar]]></title>
    <link href="http://dougsko.github.io/blog/2013/08/12/adding-a-support-bar/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-12T14:03:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://dougsko.github.io/blog/2013/08/12/adding-a-support-bar</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After flooding the table and observing how the frame held everything, I
noticed that the table was sagging some in the middle.  This was causing
the table to not drain as effectively, so I decided to build a support
bar into the middle.  Here are some pictures of the final product.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/3d0nuBx.jpg" title="'Support bar'" >
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/Qh6TkK8.jpg" title="'Support bar 2'" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grow log - 8/12/13]]></title>
    <link href="http://dougsko.github.io/blog/2013/08/12/grow-log-8-slash-12-slash-13/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-12T13:02:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://dougsko.github.io/blog/2013/08/12/grow-log-8-slash-12-slash-13</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, I added some nutrients to the water.  I&rsquo;m using the Flora
Grow nutrient system, which consists of three parts, Gro, Bloom, and
Micro.  I added 4 tsp of each to the reservoir.</p>

<p>The cucumber plant has shot up pretty quickly.  It&rsquo;s already about an an
inch and a half tall.  Since it was doing so well, I moved it to its own
pot.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/yonnynT.jpg" title="'Cucumber'" ></p>

<p>Not sure what these are, but they&rsquo;re also growing pretty quickly.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/TrqB46R.jpg" title="'Seedlings'" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grow log - 8/9/13]]></title>
    <link href="http://dougsko.github.io/blog/2013/08/09/grow-log-8-slash-9-slash-13/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-09T12:53:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://dougsko.github.io/blog/2013/08/09/grow-log-8-slash-9-slash-13</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I didn&rsquo;t label my plants so I actually have no idea what&rsquo;s what yet.
Two cubes have just barely began to sprout.  I stacked their pots on top
of other pots in order to get them closer to the light.  The lights are
on 18 hours a day.  I also added some foil to the lights to act as
reflectors until I come up with a more permanant solution.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/E571RXM.jpg" title="'Pots'" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grow log - 8/6/13]]></title>
    <link href="http://dougsko.github.io/blog/2013/08/06/grow-log-8-slash-6-slash-13/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-06T11:58:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://dougsko.github.io/blog/2013/08/06/grow-log-8-slash-6-slash-13</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I picked up the following seeds to grow in this garden:</p>

<ul>
<li>Cucumbers</li>
<li>Collard greens</li>
<li>Parsley</li>
<li>Cilantro</li>
<li>Rosemary</li>
<li>Eggplant</li>
<li>Basil</li>
<li>Dill</li>
<li>Broccoli</li>
<li>Brussels Sprouts</li>
</ul>


<p>I planted the seeds in &frac12;&#8221; rockwool cubes and then placed all the cubes
in two flower pots with some expanded clay pellets on the bottom.  I
covered the pots lightly with some plastic wrap in order to increase the
humidity.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ebb and flow, finishing the build]]></title>
    <link href="http://dougsko.github.io/blog/2013/08/06/ebb-and-flow/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-06T11:34:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://dougsko.github.io/blog/2013/08/06/ebb-and-flow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the table and lights completed, what I needed next were some drain
fittings.  One fitting is connected to the water pump and the other acts
as an overflow guard.  The overflow tube limits how deep the water can
get in the flood table, protecting you from flooding your house.  I used
a 1-3/8&#8221; spade bit to drill the holes in the flood table for the
fittings.  Once they were in place, I added the tubing, and a 20 gallon
storage container to act as the reservoir.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/6gOgTQC.jpg" title="'Finished table'" ></p>

<p>You&rsquo;ll notice I started some seeds in rockwool cubes and placed then on
the table.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building a hydroponic garden]]></title>
    <link href="http://dougsko.github.io/blog/2013/07/23/building-a-hydroponic-garden/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-23T10:27:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://dougsko.github.io/blog/2013/07/23/building-a-hydroponic-garden</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I wanted to do some gardening in my apartment and so decided that a
hydroponic system would be the best route.  Such a system would offer
the most efficiency and capacity, while taking up the least amount of
space.  I decided to go with an ebb and flow system since it would offer
the most versatility.  The way it would work is, a table would sit above
a reservoir, filled with nutrient solution, which would be pumped up to
the table periodically, and then drain back down.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I would need a structure to hold the flood table as well as something to
hold my lights, so I decided on PVC because it&rsquo;s cheap and you can make
almost anything out of it.  In order to help myself figure out how many
tee fitting, etc. I needed, I thought it&rsquo;d be a good idea to model out
the structure before buying anything.  I used Sketchup to do this since
it&rsquo;s free and someone else already modeled out all the PVC connectors I
would need.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/3r1dDEP.png" title="Model front view" alt="Model front view">
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/RNmFVmE.png" title="Model iso view" alt="Model iso view">
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/i4n1fdF.png" title="Model side view" alt="Model side view">
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/pfgFwaX.png" title="Model top view" alt="Model top view"></p>

<p>You&rsquo;ll notice the lights don&rsquo;t exactly connect to anything in the model,
but they&rsquo;re there to act more as placeholders than anything else.  Now
that I had a plan, the next step was to get started on construction.</p>

<p>I needed to make the table modular so I could get it in and out of
doorways.  So the legs, the vertical pieces that hold the light bar, and
the light bar, are all separate pieces.  Here is the table without the
top pieces:</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/9Ek9SGD.jpg" title="'Beginning of the table'" ></p>

<p>The vertical pipes that hold the light bar are how I will adjust the
height of the lights.  When I need to raise the lights up, I just swap
out those pipes for taller ones.  Here is a picture of the tall vertical
pieces with the light bar on top:</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/Z0uQSW7.jpg" title="'Tall pipes'" ></p>

<p>This next picture is a closeup of the light bar, and it shows how I&rsquo;m
actually connecting my lights.  The lights I&rsquo;m using are two 65 watt
compact fluorescent flood lights.  Each one has a &frac12;&#8221; knuckle that
would normally screw into a junction box.  In my case, they screw into
this &frac12;&#8221; threaded female reducer.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/MUmZO5J.jpg" title="'Tee fitting for light'" ></p>

<p>On the backside of the tee fitting, I drilled a hole for the lights&#8217;
wires to come through.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/Qow57Ev.jpg" title="'Tee backside'" ></p>

<p>And here is a picture of the completed table, with the lights installed:</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/eny9WLX.jpg" title="'Table complete'" ></p>

<p>And lastly, this picture shows the table with its short vertical light
holders.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/unetKnz.jpg" title="'Table short'" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
